<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carl&#39;s New Website</title>
    <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Carl&#39;s New Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 12:45:26 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://carl-tracy.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>History of carl-tracy.com</title>
      <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 12:45:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/history/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer First off let me say that I am by no means an authority on web technology, I wanted to re-do my website and part of that is making content. Writing is one of the things that I really suck at doing so I&amp;rsquo;m basically forcing myself to do it here, and part of that is discussing the technologies I&amp;rsquo;ve used over the years to build it.
How my websites were built The early days Back in the mid to late 90s, around the time I was graduating from college, the web started to become a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiktok Shortcode for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/tiktok-shortcode-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 10:15:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/tiktok-shortcode-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Tiktok shortcode for Hugo When i was trying to post my adorable Tiktok of a wee baby duck that was just hatching, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything about embedding Tiktoks into Hugo. I tried just pasting the embed code into a markdown page, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t work so I wrote a quick and dirty shortcode to do it:
tiktok.html: Save this code in \layouts\shortcodes\tiktok.html
&amp;lt;script async src=&amp;#34;https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;blockquote class=&amp;#34;tiktok-embed&amp;#34; cite=&amp;#34;https://www.tiktok.com/{{ .Get &amp;#34;usr&amp;#34; }}/video/{{ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baby Duck</title>
      <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/baby-duck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 10:02:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/baby-duck/</guid>
      <description>Please enjoy this Tiktok of a baby duck hatching =)   @chaos46692 
Music   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formula for the Weighted Average Life of a Mortgage</title>
      <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/mortgage-wal-formula/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 11:35:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/mortgage-wal-formula/</guid>
      <description>A while ago for work I had created a process that required a formula for the weighted average life (WAL) of a mortgage with level payments. I found one online:
$$ W = N D_N - \frac{1}{r} $$
where:
$$ \begin{aligned}
d &amp;amp;= { 1 \over 1 + r} = \hbox{one month discount factor} \\[7pt] r &amp;amp;= {a \over 12} = \hbox{monthly discount} \\[10pt] N &amp;amp;= \hbox{Loan period in months} \\[10pt] D_n &amp;amp;= {1 \over 1-d^n} \end{aligned}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Hugo with SSL and MathJax</title>
      <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/setting-up-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 09:44:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/setting-up-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of fun setting up Hugo to set it up how I want. I will caveat this with a few things - I tried to do things the right way (not editing the theme directly) but I&amp;rsquo;m really really really fucking impatient and in a lot of cases I just edited the theme because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with this shit. I&amp;rsquo;m never going to update it so screw it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up an SSL cetificate</title>
      <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/setting-up-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 09:02:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/setting-up-ssl/</guid>
      <description>While setting up this website I was constantly greeted by this in my address bar:
I have no real reason for it to piss me off but it surely did. This must be remedied.
My hosting is different from my registrar/DNS so accomplishing it took a little more work than it might if you have all that stuff in one place. I use namecheap as my registrar/DNS and HostPapa for my hosting (mostly because I used to use Lunarpages and they got bought by HostPapa).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Worked</title>
      <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/it-worked/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 17:02:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/it-worked/</guid>
      <description>Well hey look it worked! That&amp;rsquo;s pretty rad. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot to add to this, mostly this post is to make sure the script that I wrote to autobuild and commit to [GitHub](git commit -a &amp;ndash;allow-empty-message) works =)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Alive</title>
      <link>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/it-is-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carl-tracy.com/posts/it-is-alive/</guid>
      <description>Hello World! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I did anything with this site. I finally got around to building something with Hugo. I kind of dig the idea of a static site generator but I generally run Windows machines so it was kind of a pain in the ass. I finally got around to installing Linux Mint on a virtual machine so now it was much easier to check out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
