<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ssl on Carl&#39;s New Website</title>
    <link>https://carltracy.com/tags/ssl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ssl on Carl&#39;s New Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 09:02:38 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://carltracy.com/tags/ssl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hosting from AWS with GitHub</title>
      <link>https://carltracy.com/posts/hosting-from-github-with-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 09:02:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carltracy.com/posts/hosting-from-github-with-aws/</guid>
      <description>#Back at it again Well I certainly haven&amp;rsquo;t done much wiht this lately. Part of that is I just feel like I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to say and part of it is the setup I had was a little too much of a pain to deploy. Because, you know, actually having to log in and push 2 or 3 buttons is so much of a pain. Anyway, I got a bug up my butt and figured out how to build things with AWS and GitHub and did a small project over at Evil Peep which has been sitting dormant for around 12 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Hugo with SSL and MathJax</title>
      <link>https://carltracy.com/posts/setting-up-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 09:44:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carltracy.com/posts/setting-up-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of fun setting up Hugo to set it up how I want. I will caveat this with a few things - I tried to do things the right way (not editing the theme directly) but I&amp;rsquo;m really really really fucking impatient and in a lot of cases I just edited the theme because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with this shit. I&amp;rsquo;m never going to update it so screw it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up an SSL cetificate</title>
      <link>https://carltracy.com/posts/setting-up-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 09:02:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carltracy.com/posts/setting-up-ssl/</guid>
      <description>While setting up this website I was constantly greeted by this in my address bar:
I have no real reason for it to piss me off but it surely did. This must be remedied.
My hosting is different from my registrar/DNS so accomplishing it took a little more work than it might if you have all that stuff in one place. I use namecheap as my registrar/DNS and HostPapa for my hosting (mostly because I used to use Lunarpages and they got bought by HostPapa).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
